A Guide to the Wade Hampton Frost Collection 1880-1938; 1938-1984
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- MISCELLANEOUS MATERIAL RE: WARING HISTORICAL LIBRARY, MEDICAL UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH CAROLINA 1988, 25 TM; 2 brochures; 1 newsletter (Box-folder 13-004)
- "THE ADMINISTRATION OF THE MEDICAL DEPARTMENT OF THE CONFEDERATE STATES ARMY, 1861-1865" 1986, 1 TM (26 pp. copy) (Box-folder 13-005)
- "AN ADDRESS DELIVERED AT THE OPENING OF THE MEDICAL COLLEGE IN CHARLESTON, S.C." BY STEPHEN ELLIOTT 1826, 1 booklet (copy) (Box-folder 13-006)
- "MALARIA AND COLONIZATION IN THE CAROLINA LOW COUNTRY, 1526-1696" BY ST. JULIEN RAVENEL CHILDS 1940, 1 article (copy) (Box-folder 13-007)
- "A HISTORY OF TRINITY CHURCH IN MARSHALL, VA, 1849-1949" BY MARY RAMEY CUNNINGHAM AND MARY FOSTER TURNER 1949, 1 booklet (Box-folder 13-008)
- "CONFEDERATES, CHLOROFORM, AND CATARACTS: JULIAN JOHN CHISOLM (1830-1903)" BY W. CURTIS WORTHINGTON, JR. 1985-86, 4 reprints (Box-folder 13-009)
- OBITUARY OF WADE HAMPTON FROST IN THE FAUQUIER DEMOCRAT 1938 May, 1 newsclipping; 1 copy of newsclipping (Box-folder 13-010)
- SUSAN FROST PARRISH: ASSORTED RESEARCH NOTES 1984-86, 1 notebook; 36 AN; 20 TD (Box-folder 13-011)
- ASSORTED SOUTH CAROLINA TRAVEL AND TOURIST INFORMATION 1985-87, 1 tourbook; 9 brochures; 3 newsclippings (Box-folder 13-012)
- MISCELLANEOUS MATERIAL RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 1981-83, 9 AN; 14 TN (Box-folder 13-013)
- "PLANNING THE FIRST SCHOOL OF HYGIENE AND PUBLIC HEALTH" BY ELIZABETH FEE n.d., 1 TM; 1 AN (Box-folder 13-014)
- WADE HAMPTON FROST MEMORIAL LECTURES AT JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 1939-82, 5 reprints; 2 TM (Box-folder 13-015)
- WADE HAMPTON FROST MEMORIAL LECTURES AT JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY "1973-75, 1982-83", 4 reprints; 2 TM (Box-folder 13-016)
- DEDICATION OF WADE HAMPTON FROST READING ROOM AT JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 1981-83, 2 booklets; 13 TL (Box-folder 14-001)
- WADE HAMPTON FROST 1935-36 (?), 7 photos B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 14-002)
- WADE HAMPTON FROST 1935-36 (?), 2 photos B&W 8 x 10; 11 x 14 (Box-folder 14-003)
- NOTES BY SUSAN FROST PARRISH TO JOAN ECHTENKAMP KLEIN RE: DONATION OF WADE HAMPTON FROST PAPERS TO THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1987, 1 TM; 1 AN; 1 TL (Box-folder 14-004)
- LISTING OF WADE HAMPTON FROST CORRESPONDENCE 1987 (?), 1 notebook (AN) (Box-folder 14-005)
- MISCELLANEOUS MATERIAL 1986, 1 TM; TL/TD (40 pp. copies) (Box-folder 14-006)
- ARTICLE ON THOMAS N. FROST (1906-1970) 1984, 1 newsclipping (Box-folder 14-007)
- SEDGWICK MEMORIAL MEDAL AWARD; FUNERAL ANNOUNCEMENTS FOR WADE HAMPTON FROST 1938, 1 newsclipping; 1 TD (Box-folder 14-008)
- MEMORIAL LECTURES/ARTICLES ON WADE HAMPTON FROST "1939, 1983", 1 magazine; 2 TM; 1 reprint (Box-folder 14-009)
- INTERVIEWS WITH ERNEST STEBBINS AND MORTON LEVIN RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST AND JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 1975 June, 2 TM (Box-folder 14-010)
- SUSAN FROST PARRISH RESEARCH NOTES "1975, 1984-85", 1 TM; 1 TN; 1 AN (Box-folder 14-011)
- LETTER FROM EDWIN FRED TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 1960 June, 1 TLS (Box-folder 14-012)
  DR. FRED WAS PRESIDENT OF UNIV. OF WISCONSIN
- LETTERS FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO JOHN RAMEY AND TO MRS. RAMEY "1895-97, 1986", 1 TLS; 3 ALS (copies) (Box-folder 14-013)
- SUSAN FROST PARRISH RESEARCH RE: SOUTH CAROLINA CONNECTION TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 1986, 7 TN; 16 articles (copies) (Box-folder 14-014)
- LETTERS FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO WADE HAMPTON FROST "1936-41, 1968", 2 TN; 12 AMS (copies) (Box-folder 14-015)
  INCLUDES OWENS' OBIT.
- ASSORTED RESEARCH NOTES/LETTERS BY SUSAN FROST PARRISH 1986-89, 7 AN; 6 TL; 1 brochure (Box-folder 14-016)
- INTERVIEWS WITH SUSAN FROST PARRISH RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 1982-83, 2 TM; 2 TNS (Box-folder 14-017)
- C. POWELL NOLAND OBITUARY 1912, 1 newsclipping; 1 copy of newsclipping (Box-folder 14-018)
- CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN SUSAN FROST PARRISH AND ANITA SMITH 1987, 6 TLS (Box-folder 14-019)
- LETTER FROM SUSAN HAXALL FROST WILLIAM H. WELCH 1933, 1 AL (copy); 1 TN (Box-folder 14-020)
- HENRY ROSE CARTER MATERIAL 1925-89, TD (80 pp. copies) (Box-folder 14-021)
- LETTER FROM SUSAN FROST PARRISH TO PHLLIP E. SARTWELL 1982 Feb., 1 TLS (Box-folder 14-022)
- PUBLIC HEALTH MAGAZINES AND ARTICLES "1945, 1950, 1976-83", 1 magazine; 7 reprints (copies) (Box-folder 14-023)
- ARTICLES RE: POLIOMYELITIS 1910-19, TL (copies) (Box-folder 15-001)
  COPIED FROM THE NATIONAL ARCHIVES
- ARTICLES RE: INFLUENZA 1918-20, TL (copies) (Box-folder 15-002)
- ARTICLES RE: WATER POLLUTION 1914-15, TL (copies) (Box-folder 15-003)
- ARTICLES RE: WATER POLLUTION 1913-16, TL (copies) (Box-folder 15-004)
- ARTICLES RE: WATER POLLUTION 1916-22, TL (copies) (Box-folder 15-005)
- ARTICLES RE: WATER POLLUTION 1913-20, TL (copies) (Box-folder 15-006)
- FROST PHOTO ALBUM/SCRAPBOOK 1935-75, scrapbook (Box-folder 16-001)
  "INCLUDES NEWSCLIPPINGS, PHOTOS, INVITATIONS, ETC."
- WADE HAMPTON FROST ca. 1935, framed photo (Box-folder 16-002)
  11.5 X 15 WITH FRAME
- WADE HAMPTON FROST ca. 1935, framed photo with card (Box-folder 16-003)
  12 X 15.5 WITH FRAME; INCLUDES CARD AND BRASS REVERSE ETCHING
- INTERVIEW WITH JAMES PERKINS 1975 June 27, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-004)
- INTERVIEW WITH MRS. EBIE ANDERSON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-005)
- INTERVIEW WITH MRS. IVAN MARTY 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-006)
  WRITING ON TAPE BARELY LEGIBLE
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ANNA BAETJER n.d., cassette tape (Box-folder 16-007)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. PHILIP E. SARTWELL 1975 June 25, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-008)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ERNEST L. STEBBINS 1975 June 24, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-009)
- INTERVIEW WITH SOPER 1975 July 26, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-010)
  WRITING ON TAPE ILLEGIBLE
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ERNEST L. STEBBINS 1975 June 24, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-011)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ANNA BAETJER n.d., cassette tape (Box-folder 16-012)
  "WRITTEN ALSO AS ""BAECKE" ON TAPE"
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ROSS GOULD 1975 July 22, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-013)
- INTERVIEW WITH MARSHALL BARTON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-014)
- INTERVIEW WITH SOPER 1975 July 26, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-015)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. JAMES PERKINS 1975 June 27, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-016)
- INTERVIEW WITH MRS. EBIE ANDERSON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-017)
- INTERVIEW WITH MRS. EBIE ANDERSON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-018)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. MORTON LEVIN 1975 June 25, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-019)
- INTERVIEW WITH MRS. IVAN MARTY 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-020)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ROSS GOULD 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-021)
- INTERVIEW WITH MARSHALL BARTON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-022)
- INTERVIEW WITH PHILIP E. SARTWELL 1975 June 25, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-023)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ABEL WOLMAN 1975 June 26, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-024)
- INTERVIEW WITH MRS. EBIE ANDERSON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-025)
- INTERVIEW WITH MARSHALL BARTON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-026)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ABEL WOLMAN 1975 June 26, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-027)
- INTERVIEW WITH MARSHALL BARTON 1975 July 23, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-028)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. MORTON LEVIN 1975 June 25, cassette tape (Box-folder 16-029)
- WADE HAMPTON FROST pre 1930, FRAMED PHOTO (Box-folder 16-030)
  8 X 10 WITH FRAME
- SIR ALEXANDER FLEMING AND STAFF 1944 JUNE, FRAMED PHOTO (Box-folder 16-031)
  7 x 9 WITH FRAME, HANDWRITTEN NOTE ON BACK: TO JACK WITH BEST REGARDS PETER AYERS DEC 1999, TYPED NOTE ON BACK INCLUDES: THIS PHOTOGRAPH OF SIR ALEXANDER FLEMING AND HIS STAFF IN THE LIBRARY OF WHAT IS NOW THE THE WRIGHT FLEMING INSTITUTE OF MICROBIOLOGY, ST. MARY'S HOSPITAL LONDON, WAS TAKEN ON THE DAY HE WAS KNIGHTED BY KING GOERGE VI, JUNE 1944.
- SEDGWICK MEMORIAL MEDAL IN CASE 1938, 2.25" IN DIAMETER BRASS-COLORED MEDAL (Box-folder 16-032)
  MEDAL STATES: AWARDED TO WADE HAMPTON FROST M.D. BY THE AMERICAN PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATION FOR DISTINGUISHED SERVICE IN PUBLIC HEALTH; MEDAL MADE BY H.P. PETERSEN, WASHINGTON, D.C.
- SUSAN HAXALL FROST n.d., photo (Box-folder A82A)
  ONE OF SEVERAL ITEMS IN WOODEN CHEST (A82)
- "FRANCIS LE JAU, D.D." n.d., photo (Box-folder A82B)
- REVEREND THOMAS FROST BY JOHN D. COGDILL 1806, photo (Box-folder A82C)
  THIS PROFILE LIKENESS WAS TAKEN FROM MEMORY IN CHARLESTON, S.C.; ONE OF SEVERAL ITEMS IN WOODEN CHEST (A82)
- FROST FAMILY COAT OF ARMS n.d., artifact (Box-folder A82D)
  E TERRA AD COELUM; ONE OF SEVERAL ITEMS IN WOODEN CHEST (A82)
- ENGRAVING, COPPER PLATE, FOR PRINTING n.d., artifact; 3.5 x 4.75 (Box-folder A82E)
- METAL ENGRAVING, PLATE, FOR PRINTING BOOKPLATES n.d., artifact; 3.25 X 6 (Box-folder A82F)
  FROST FAMILY COAT OF ARMS; ONE OF SEVERAL ITEMS IN WOODEN CHEST (A82)
- SEDGWICK MEMORIAL MEDAL FOR WADE HAMPTON FROST 1938, artifact (Box-folder A82G)
- WATCH CASE OF WADE HAMPTON FROST n.d., artifact; leather and velvet (Box-folder A82H)
- WATCH, POCKET, WITH CHAIN, OF WADE HAMPTON FROST n.d., artifact; metal and glass (Box-folder A82H)
- UNKNOWN FEMALE SUBJECT, PROBABLY A RELATIVE OF WADE HAMPTON FROST n.d., miniature in case (Box-folder A82I)
- GOLD RING WITH FROST COAT OF ARMS n.d., artifact (Box-folder A82J)
- HAIRPIN WITH GEM AND PEARL CAP, PROBABLY FROM FEMALE RELATIVE OF WADE HAMPTON FROST n.d., artifact (Box-folder A82K)
- STAMP WITH FAMILY COAT OF ARMS - PROBABLY NOT FROST FAMILY n.d., artifact; metal and glass (Box-folder A82L)
  LUCEO NON URO; ONE OF SEVERAL ITEMS IN WOODEN CHEST (A82)
- WOODEN CHEST, PRESUMABLY BELONGING TO WADE HAMPTON FROST n.d., chest/footlocker w/ assorted WADE HAMPTON FROST belongings (Box-folder A82M)
  CONTAINS FROST PHOTOGRAPHS AND ARTIFACTS